Arch Oboler Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 5. Manuscripts, 1920-1986, 11.3 linear feet (27 boxes)
  - Articles and stories, 1920-1983
    - "For Roth," undated (Box 134, Folder 4)
      Five miscellaneous manuscripts.
    - Forbes project synopsis, 1984 January (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - "Forever Amber," town file, 1957 August, October (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - "Forever Green," town file, undated (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Various Frank Lloyd Wright articles, 1957 October and undated (Box 134, Folder 8)
    - Future articles list, undated (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - The Great Observer Hole, 1976 April (Box 134, Folder 10)
    - The Greatest in the World, undated (Box 134, Folder 11)
    - Her Other Self, 1938 (Box 134, Folder 12)
    - Hold My Hand, undated (Box 134, Folder 13)
    - Hollywood Discovers Science Fiction, undated (Box 134, Folder 14)
    - Hollywood story (Zion trip), 1957 July (Box 134, Folder 15)
    - "How Boy Scouts Aided Carr & Son Canvass," Talking Machine World, 1927 June (Box 134, Folder 16)
    - "In Fourth Dimension by Film," Citizen-News, undated (Box 134, Folder 17)
    - In Memory with a Crystal Ball, undated (Box 134, Folder 18)
    - Jackasses & I, 1975 October (Box 134, Folder 19)
    - Jackasses, 1975 October (Box 134, Folder 20)
      Original for xerox.
    - King Midas & His Golden Woman, undated (Box 134, Folder 21)
    - Listen Amtrak, Dogs Can Fly, 1976 June-November (Box 134, Folder 22)
    - The "Lost" Art Form, undated (Box 134, Folder 23)
    - Short story version of "The Machine," (change to green label) fire file, undated (Box 134, Folder 24)
    - "Maker of Monsters in the Mind," Los Angeles Times, undated (Box 134, Folder 25)
    - "Man of the House," 1950 January (Box 134, Folder 26)
    - Me and My Classic/Classics, 1982 January-February (Box 134, Folder 27)
    - "Me or Him," 1946 October (Box 134, Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous articles, principally concerning 3-D, 1953 February-1955 February and undated (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Mobile, Are You Through? undated (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Moe & Schmoe, 1976 March (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Movies Are Better Than Ever - in the Next Decade, undated (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - "The Murder Game," Nickel Detective, 1933 August (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - My Jackasses and the Fire, Coronet, 1960 June (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - My Soup's On/The Greatest in the World, undated (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - My Turn (Amtrak, Listen! Dogs Can Fly!), undated (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - My Wife - Before and After, undated (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - "The Night of Ka-Sam," 1936 May (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - The Nostalgic Saga of Bwana Devil 3-D, 1977 February-April (Box 135, Folder 11)
    - "Nude at High Noon," National Observer, 1976 May 29 (Box 135, Folder 12)
    - Untitled articles, circa 1930 (Box 135, Folder 13-15)
    - Old Dog/A Time to Dream, Good Housekeeping, 1968 February-May and undated (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Old time radio manuscript, undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - The One Bullet: A Story by Archie Oboler, undated (Box 136, Folder 3)
      Advertisement.
    - Operation Eyeball, 1954 January 6 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - "Pardon My Mal de Mer," circa 1948 (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Pioneers in a Covered Van (Volks Wagon), 1976 September (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Playboy story idea/L.A. Off, 1975 February (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - The Pool & I, 1975 July (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - A Prayer, 1954 November-December (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - A Princess Comes to Call, The National Observer, 1975 September 27 (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - Rabbits, 1983 May (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - "Remember That Physicians Are Not Gods," The National Observer, 1976 March 27 (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - Rest in Video Peace, undated (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - The Rockford File, 1960 January (Box 136, Folder 14)
    - Rocks in My Head, undated (Box 136, Folder 15)
    - The Saga of Helga, undated (Box 136, Folder 16)
    - Samuel Sadim, undated (Box 136, Folder 17)
    - Scare Me, 1982 February (Box 136, Folder 18)
    - "Smell of Death," town file, [1946 June?] (Box 136, Folder 19)
    - "Snob," town and fire files, undated (Box 136, Folder 20)
    - A Sour Apple for Hollywood as a Teacher, undated (Box 136, Folder 21)
      Fragment.
    - "The Specialist," town and fire files, circa 1950 (Box 136, Folder 22)
      Original short story.
    - "Strange Morning," town file, undated (Box 136, Folder 23)
    - "The Thing from Beyond," 1941 October (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - The Tree & I, undated (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - Trouble, 1958 September 22 (Box 137, Folder 3)
      Proposed story in a letter to Jack Paar.
    - The True Africa, undated (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Turnabout Club, 1961 September (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - The Visit (A Fable for Our Time), undated (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - VW: Model Future, town file, 1959 January (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Was It Satan at Work? The National Observer, 1976 August 28 (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - What Would You Have Done, undated (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Who Thought of It First, 1982 February (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - Wright Memories, undated (Box 137, Folder 11)
  - Books, 1944-1986
    - Beware the Fury, 1971-1975
      - Beware the Fury, 1971-1975 (Box 137, Folder 12-17)
      - Beware the Fury: A Novel, undated (Box 138, Folder 1-4)
      - Brandon & Rogers, undated (Box 138, Folder 5-6)
      - Novel by Arch Oboler, 1975, (1 folder) (Box 138-139, Box 138, Box 139)
      - Loose pages, 1975 April (Box 139, Folder 2)
      - Original, 1975 March 8 (Box 139, Folder 3-4)
      - Miscellaneous Beware the Fury/Golden Man, 1973-1975 (Box 139, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous Big Ben/Beware the Fury/Golden Man, 1973-1974 (Box 139, Folder 6)
      - Pre New York xerox master, 1975 May 4 (Box 139, Folder 7-8)
      - Big Ben/Beware the Fury, loose pages, 1973 March-1975 February (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Big Ben, 1971-1974
      - Fragments, 1971-1974 (Box 139, Folder 10)
      - Fragments, 1973 April-May (Box 140, Folder 1)
      - Golden, 1974 (Box 140, Folder 2)
      - Original and carbons, undated (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Golden Man, 1973-1975
      - Golden Man, 1973-1975 (Box 140, Folder 4-5)
      - Draft of first chapter and outline, Kurt Hellmer, undated (Box 140, Folder 6)
      - Loose pages, 1974-1975 (Box 140, Folder 7-9)
    - New novel [Big Ben?], undated (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - 72 Hours, 1971 September-November (Box 140, Folder 11)
    - Daddy, Where Are You?, 1986 and undated
      - Draft fragment on legal paper, undated (Box 140, Folder 12)
      - First draft of original, undated (Box 141, Folder 1-2)
      - Incomplete fragment, undated (Box 141, Folder 3-4)
      - Daddy, Where are You? 1986 April (Box 141, Folder 5)
      - Daddy, Where are You?: a novel by Molly Ti, undated (Box 141, Folder 6-7)
      - Revisions, undated (Box 142, Folder 1-3)
    - Diamond Cut Diamond, 1968and undated
      - Original carbon of the final version plus Oboler's carbon copy, undated (Box 142, Folder 4)
      - Carbon copy of rough draft, 1968 April-May (Box 142, Folder 5)
      - Rough draft and second version, Oboler's carbon copies, 1968 February-May (Box 142, Folder 6)
      - Second revision, 1968 (Box 143, Folder 1)
      - Short version, 1968 February (Box 143, Folder 2)
        First and second versions submitted to Kurt Hellmer.
      - Oboler, EO, and JK notes plus extra pages, 1968 February-September (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Great Green Diamond novel, carbon copy, first rough, 1968 (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Fly with a Cherub, circa 1954-1983 and undated
      - Fly with a Cherub, undated (Box 143, Folder 5)
      - Novel, circa 1954 (Box 143, Folder 6-8)
      - New novel version, undated (Box 143, Folder 9)
      - Surprise, Fly with a Cherub, 1981 December, 1983 July, and undated (Box 143, Folder 10-11)
    - Surprise, novel, 1983 (Box 143, Folder 12)
    - Happy Holiday, undated (Box 144, Folder 1-6)
    - Hollywood stars book, undated (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - House on Fire, 1968-1969 and undated
      - House on Fire: a Novel, undated (Box 145, Folder 1-3)
      - By Arch Oboler, circa 1968 (Box 145, Folder 4-5)
      - House on Fire magazine advertisements, undated (Box OS 2, Folder 7)
      - Oboler's final copy, 1969 January-February (Box 145, Folder 6)
      - Extra pages, research, etc., 1968-1969 (Box 146, Folder 1-2)
      - First typing, carbon, 1968-1969 (Box 146, Folder 3-4)
      - New revisions and changes, 1969 April-May (Box 146, Folder 5-6)
      - Original with corrections, 1968-1969 (Box 146-147)
        - (1 folder) (Box 146)
        - (1 folder) (Box 147)
      - Scenes and chronology, 1969 April 14 (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - The Jackasses and I
      - Various chapters, town file, circa 1964 (Box 147, Folder 3-5)
      - Book, 1976 March (Box 147, Folder 6)
      - Dogs, undated (Box 147, Folder 7)
      - Novel, various chapters, 1964 November (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Lights Out book
      - Book, undated (Box 148, Folder 2-4)
      - Book, 1973-1974 (Box 148, Folder 5)
      - Town file, undated (Box 148, Folder 6-7)
      - Lights Out by Arch Oboler: 13 Dramas of the Supernatural, circa 1982 (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Miracle/Negative Miracle, 1974 January (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Elizabeth, 1969
      Novel.
      - "Rough," 1969 February-March (Box 149, Folder 2)
      - New novel, 1969 February (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Mr. Dinghy, 1969-1970
      - Mr. Dinghy, 1969-1970 (Box 149, Folder 4-6)
      - Synopsis, 1969 February-1970 January (Box 149, Folder 7)
      - Novel version, 1969 June 18 (Box 149, Folder 8)
      - Old pages retyped, undated (Box 149, Folder 9)
      - Revision, undated (Box 149, Folder 10)
      - Notes, 1970 February (Box 149, Folder 11)
    - Nature of the Beast, 1970-1974
      - Breakdown, 1970 November 12 (Box 149, Folder 12)
      - "Nature Beast, 1974," 1970 July-1974 July (Box 149, Folder 13-14)
      - Undated material, undated (Box 150, Folder 1-2)
      - Nature of the Beast: A Novel, undated, 260 pages. (Box 150, Folder 3-4)
      - With revisions, undated, 260 pages. (Box 150, Folder 5-6)
      - Nature of the Beast: A Novel, undated (Box 151, Folder 1-2)
      - From Bartholomew, undated (Box 151, Folder 3-4)
      - Kurt Hellmer, undated (Box 151, Folder 5-6)
      - [Nature of the Beast?] synopsis, undated (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Oboler Omnibus, 1945 (Box 151, Folder 8-9)
    - Original "Point a Fiery Finger," 1974 January (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Outline, Point of View, undated (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - Radio scripts book, untitled, undated (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - The Ranch and I outline, undated (Box 152, Folder 4)
      Book.
    - Sixteen New Radio Plays by Arch Oboler, undated (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Special Delivery, 1968 and undated
      - Special Delivery, undated (Box 152, Folder 6)
      - [Special Delivery?] by Norm Bobrow, undated (Box 152, Folder 7-10)
      - Synopsis, 1968 August (Box 152, Folder 11)
    - Story idea, Night Clouds, undated (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - This Freedom, fire file, 1944 July-August (Box 152, Folder 13)
  - Readers Digest, 1944-1981
    - "Bacchanal," fire file, undated (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - "Bacchanal," not sold, 1955-1968 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - "Cliff for My Enemy," fire file, circa 1959 January (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - "Cliff for My Enemy," town file, circa 1959 March (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - "Don't Tread on Me," 1958 December-1959 March (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - E.S.P. article, fire file, circa 1958 July-September (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - E.S.P. article, town file, circa 1958 July-September (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - Ehrmann article, fire file, circa 1958 November - 1959 April (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Ehrmann article, town file, circa 1959 January-April (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - "Eleanor Versus Africa," 1948 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - "Eleanor Versus Africa," fire file, circa 1956 October - 1957 May (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - "Forever Green," fire file, undated (Box 153, Folder 12)
    - "Haunted Honeymoon," fire file, circa 1958 March (Box 153, Folder 13)
    - "Haunted Honeymoon," town file, circa 1958 March - May (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - "He's Always Magnificently Wright," town file, 1958 March (Box 154, Folder 2-3)
    - "I'm in Love with Bubbles," fire file, 1958 (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - "I'm in Love with Bubbles," town file, 1958 September (Box 154, Folder 5-7)
    - "Jackasses and I," 1957 May-1964 November (Box 154, Folder 8)
    - "Jackasses and I," fire file, circa 1956 May (Box 154, Folder 9)
    - "Leon," fire file, 1954 October, circa 1959 (Box 154, Folder 10)
    - "Leon," town file, undated (Box 154, Folder 11)
    - "Lion by the Tail," fire file, circa 1959 August (Box 155, Folder 1)
    - "Man of the House," town file, circa 1959 (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - "Me and My Foreign Bomb," fire file, 1958 June (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - "Me and My Foreign Bomb," town file, circa 1957, 1958 June (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - "The Most Unforgettable Character I've Met," undated (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - "My African Poltergeist," 1981 December (Box 155, Folder 6)
    - "My Greatest Adventure in Living," fire file, 1944 October (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - "My Greatest Adventure in Living," town file, undated (Box 155, Folder 8)
    - O'Brien letter, 1971 September 16 (Box 155, Folder 9)
    - "Peter's Story," town file, circa 1958 (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - "A Princess Comes A-Calling," 1971 August-1972 September (Box 155, Folder 11)
    - Princess, 1972 March-August (Box 155, Folder 12)
    - "Princess Where Are You," 1981 May-June (Box 155, Folder 13)
    - Reader's Digest, June 1958, town file, 1958 June (Box 155, Folder 14)
    - Rock story, 1958 February-1959 December (Box 155, Folder 15)
    - "Satan Is Alive and Well in California," 1973 June-November (Box 155, Folder 16)
    - Unsold manuscripts, circa 1965 (Box 155, Folder 17)
    - VW-Model Future, fire file, circa 1958 August (Box 155, Folder 18)
  - Short stories, 1927-1948 and undated
    - Shore story collection notes (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - "Advice Is Advice," undated (Box 156, Folder 2)
    - "All Bets Off," undated (Box 156, Folder 3)
    - "Amachoors," undated (Box 156, Folder 4)
    - "And He Learned About Winning from Her," undated (Box 156, Folder 5)
    - "Bark and Bite," undated (Box 156, Folder 6)
    - "Be in at Twelve, Mary!," undated (Box 156, Folder 7)
    - "Bequest: A Short Story," undated (Box 156, Folder 8)
    - "The Better Man," undated (Box 156, Folder 9)
    - "Big Business Bill," undated (Box 156, Folder 10)
    - "Big Sister," undated (Box 156, Folder 11)
    - "Blood Drips," undated (Box 156, Folder 12)
    - "The Blue Overalls Election," undated (Box 156, Folder 13)
    - "Boomeranging Bullets," undated (Box 156, Folder 14)
    - "Brainy Blonde," undated (Box 156, Folder 15)
    - "The Brown Door (Chicago Tales)," undated (Box 156, Folder 16)
    - "Brown Skips a House," undated (Box 156, Folder 17)
    - "Burnt," undated (Box 156, Folder 18)
    - "Chicago Tale: A Series," undated (Box 156, Folder 19)
    - "The Chinese Way," undated (Box 156, Folder 20)
    - "The Circus Terror," undated (Box 156, Folder 21)
    - "Collegiate Knuckles," undated (Box 156, Folder 22)
    - "Conversion," undated (Box 156, Folder 23)
    - "The Crime Clique of Croesus," undated (Box 156, Folder 24)
    - "Day of Reckoning," undated (Box 156, Folder 25)
    - "Dead Man's Revenge," undated (Box 156, Folder 26)
    - "Death Buddha," undated (Box 156, Folder 27)
    - "Death by Poison," undated (Box 156, Folder 28)
    - "Delusion," undated (Box 156, Folder 29)
    - "Donaldson Acquires 'Close-Ability,'" undated (Box 156, Folder 30)
    - "The Dope on Louie," undated (Box 156, Folder 31)
    - "The Double-Crossed," undated (Box 156, Folder 32)
    - "Dynamite Death," undated (Box 156, Folder 33)
    - "Enlightenment," undated (Box 156, Folder 34)
    - "The Evil One," undated (Box 156, Folder 35)
    - "Examination in the Nude," undated (Box 156, Folder 36)
    - "Fake," undated (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - "The Fast One," undated (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - "First Stones," undated (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - "Five Keys to a Million," undated (Box 157, Folder 4)
    - "Flip a Coin," undated (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - "Fool Man," undated (Box 157, Folder 6)
    - "French Pick-up," undated (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - "From a Diary at 19," 1933 (Box 157, Folder 8)
    - "The Game of Death," undated (Box 157, Folder 9)
    - "Gangster Hate," undated (Box 157, Folder 10)
    - "The Gems in the Smoke," undated (Box 157, Folder 11)
    - "Give a Man Advice," undated (Box 157, Folder 12)
    - "A Good Reputation," circa 1927 (Box 157, Folder 13)
    - "The Great Swami Racket," undated (Box 157, Folder 14)
    - "Hate," undated (Box 157, Folder 15-16)
    - "Have a Smoke," undated (Box 157, Folder 17)
    - "Headlines," undated (Box 157, Folder 18)
    - "Hick Stuff," undated (Box 157, Folder 19)
    - "High Hat," undated (Box 157, Folder 20)
    - "His Lordship's Damaged Eye," 1946 (Box 157, Folder 21)
    - "Honesty," undated (Box 157, Folder 22)
    - "Humbug," undated (Box 157, Folder 23)
    - "Iron Box," undated (Box 157, Folder 24)
    - "J. Bodwine Browne Confesses," undated (Box 157, Folder 25)
    - "J. Gillan's Hootenany Write-up," undated (Box 157, Folder 26)
    - "Joe Piper and the Obstacles," undated (Box 157, Folder 27)
    - "Knock-out," undated (Box 157, Folder 28)
    - "Lady Counsellor," undated (Box 157, Folder 29)
    - "Lady of the Evening," undated (Box 157, Folder 30)
    - "Last Flight," undated (Box 157, Folder 31)
    - "Lead Curtains," undated (Box 157, Folder 32)
    - "Lead Legacy," undated (Box 157, Folder 33)
    - "The Left-Handed Murder," undated (Box 157, Folder 34)
    - "Like Ma Brud,'" undated (Box 157, Folder 35)
    - "A Little Fun," undated (Box 157, Folder 36)
    - "Loose Nut," undated (Box 157, Folder 37)
    - "The Love Bet," undated (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - "Love Factor 100%," undated (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - "Lucky Joe," undated (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - "The Machine," undated (Box 158, Folder 4)
    - "The Mandarin's Head," undated (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - "Man Eater," undated (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - "A Man with Guts," undated (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - "Marry the Girl," undated (Box 158, Folder 8-9)
    - "Massacre," undated (Box 158, Folder 10)
    - "A Matter of Great Import," undated (Box 158, Folder 11)
    - "Memo: Raise for Mr. Snipes," undated (Box 158, Folder 12)
    - "Mike Closes a Deal," undated (Box 158, Folder 13)
    - "Mine," undated (Box 158, Folder 14)
    - "Miracle Apartments," undated (Box 158, Folder 15)
    - "Miss Information," undated (Box 158, Folder 16)
    - "Mixed Dates," undated (Box 158, Folder 17)
    - "Mr. Applebaum Fixes Things," undated (Box 158, Folder 18)
    - "Mr. Whiff's Emancipating Pants," undated (Box 158, Folder 19)
    - "Murder Below," undated (Box 158, Folder 20)
    - "Murder Upstairs," undated (Box 158, Folder 21)
    - "My Radio Sweethearts," undated (Box 158, Folder 22)
    - "The Mystery-Master Murder," undated (Box 158, Folder 23)
    - "The Night of Ka-Sam," undated (Box 158, Folder 24)
    - "Noble Guy," undated (Box 158, Folder 25)
    - "Nothing Ever Happens - Much!" undated (Box 158, Folder 26)
    - "Nude on the Roof," undated (Box 158, Folder 27)
    - "The One Bullet," undated (Box 158, Folder 28)
    - "Out of the Tomb," undated (Box 158, Folder 29)
    - "Pardon My Error," 1927 (Box 158, Folder 30)
    - "Pardon My Mal de Mer," undated (Box 158, Folder 31)
    - "The Phony Demo," undated (Box 158, Folder 32)
    - "The Phony Graphic Invention," undated (Box 158, Folder 33)
    - "Practical Joke," undated (Box 158, Folder 34)
    - "Principles," undated (Box 158, Folder 35)
    - "The Radio Alibi," 1945, undated (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - "Rat-hunt," undated (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - "The Reckoning," undated (Box 159, Folder 3)
    - "Refugee," undated (Box 159, Folder 4)
    - "Rendezvous," undated (Box 159, Folder 5)
    - "Sacrifice of Blood," undated (Box 159, Folder 6)
    - "Sakhalin," undated (Box 159, Folder 7)
    - "The Second Mail," undated (Box 159, Folder 8)
    - "Set-up," undated (Box 159, Folder 9)
    - "Sly Adventure," undated (Box 159, Folder 10)
    - "Smart Guy," undated (Box 159, Folder 11)
    - "The Speed Man," undated (Box 159, Folder 12)
    - "The Spot," undated (Box 159, Folder 13)
    - "The Squad Car Murders," undated (Box 159, Folder 14)
    - "Stick to Your Own Knitting," undated (Box 159, Folder 15)
    - "Strange Morning," undated (Box 159, Folder 16)
    - "Such a Handsome Man," undated (Box 159, Folder 17)
    - "Summer at the Shack," undated (Box 159, Folder 18)
    - "Suppressed Desires," undated (Box 159, Folder 19)
    - "Surprise," undated (Box 159, Folder 20)
    - "Suspicion," undated (Box 159, Folder 21)
    - "The Tamasculo Overall Revolt," undated (Box 159, Folder 22)
    - "A Temper Like Mac's," undated (Box 159, Folder 23)
    - "That Fellow Known as Paul," undated (Box 159, Folder 24)
    - "The Thing Below," undated (Box 159, Folder 25)
    - "Tough Georgie," undated (Box 159, Folder 26)
    - "Tough Stakes," undated (Box 159, Folder 27)
    - "Treasure," undated (Box 159, Folder 28)
    - "Try and Tell-a-Vision!" undated (Box 159, Folder 29)
    - "Twenty-one Years," undated (Box 159, Folder 30)
    - "Two Lucky Pennies," undated (Box 159, Folder 31)
    - "Two Thousand Dollar Kiss," 1948 (Box 159, Folder 32)
    - "The Ultimate Sucker," undated (Box 159, Folder 33)
    - "Understanding," undated (Box 159, Folder 34)
    - "Video Vable," undated (Box 159, Folder 35)
    - "When Greek Meets Greek," (Box 159, Folder 36)
    - "Whom the Shoe Pinches," (Box 159, Folder 37)
    - "Young Men Like Them Old (Old Men Like Them Young)," (Box 159, Folder 38)
- Series 6. Miscellaneous, 1916-1992, 1.7 linear feet (4 boxes)
  The Miscellaneous series contains biographical material such as entertainment industry magazine articles, principally on Oboler but also about Oboler family members. There is biographical information on his assistant Jerry Kay (whose original name was Geraldine Klancke), and there are Oboler materials Kay evidently compiled for sales efforts after his death. Scrapbooks kept by Oboler as a youth show his early interests in nature. A number of folders entitled “Ideas” from his career in radio and afterwards, in general chronologically arranged, show his creative processes at work.
  - Miscellaneous biographical, family, and personal materials, 1936-1987
    - Arch Oboler biographical and other newspaper and magazine clippings, 1936 June-1942 May (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - NBC publications about Oboler, 1938 March-1942 January (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - Radio Life magazine article: "Arch Oboler: A Master Dramatist Readies New Shocker," 1940 August 18 (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - Joint will of Arch Oboler and Eleanor Helfand Oboler, 1941 March 8 (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - Pic magazine article: "Arch Oboler with the Gnome-like Puss," 1941 March 4 (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - New York Times newspaper article: "The Radio Scene: Some Opinions, Bulletins: Mr. Oboler Again," 1942 November 15 (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - Radio Life magazine article: "Arch Oboler Tells How to Get into Radio," 1942 November 22 (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Tune In magazine article: "Lights Out: Arch Oboler's Blood Chilling Dramas Are Full of Technical Innovations," 1943 August (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - Radio-Television Life magazine article: "Photocade of a Decade," 1950 March 3 (Box 160, Folder 9)
    - Arch Oboler biographies, circa 1956-circa 1973 (Box 160, Folder 10)
    - Guy Oboler - Ridgewood Military Academy promotion certificate, 1957 June (Box 160, Folder 11)